♪ In the not too distant
Future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
From you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
In a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
Cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
Didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him
Cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
And watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
La la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
Begin or end la-la-la ♪
♪ Because he used
Those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
- ♪ Robot roll call... ♪
- ♪ Cambot... ♪
- ♪ Pan left ♪
- ♪ Gypsy... ♪
- ♪ Hi girl ♪
- ♪ Tom Servo... ♪
- ♪ What a cool guy ♪
- ♪ Croooow! ♪
- ♪ He's a wisecracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La la la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
"It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax" ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
[Coughing]
- Oh, yuck!
Joel! Pfft!
There's soap
all in my mouth
and it tastes like
it might be [indistinct].
- Hey kiddo,
that's good stuff, come on.
- Yeah, it's got one quarter
cleansing cream.
- No, that's dumb!
[Crying]
- Hey, everybody,
it's a bad day around here.
It's annual wash and wax day,
the most dreaded day of all.
You can't go near Joel
or he'll scrub you
to a pink pulp.
- Oh, hi everybody,
welcome to the S.O.L.,
it's really lucky
you happened by.
It's our annual
wash and wax day, it's...
- Wash and wax, wash and wax.
- ...one of the funnest
days of all!
[Tom yelling]
- Okay, Tom,
if you can hear me,
you want to close your mouth.
The buffers are coming by.
- Isn't it horrifying?
- Buh buh buh buh buh...
- Okay Tom,
you're almost done.
I need Crow T...
COMPUTER VOICE:
Commercial sign in five seconds.
Crow sighting over by Cambot.
- You'll never take me alive!
[♪♪♪]
[Crying]
- Ha ha! Boy, I feel great,
that was just wonderful.
Hey, who wants
to go for a walk?
♪ Rent boys are delicious ♪
♪ Delicious
Candy colored love... ♪
- Shut up! Shut up!
Joel, make him stop.
- I'm sorry, your what hurts?
- Oh, come on, Crow.
Take it easy.
You made it through,
you're gonna be okay.
Come on,
I'll give you a Zagnut bar
if you can simmer down.
- No!
- How about another
Nutter Butter peanut butter
sandwich cookie?
- No!
- Well, what do I have to do
to make it all better?
- I want you to beat up Tom.
- Oh, hey. You got your
hands full with that one, huh?
Well, gotta go.
♪ Give me a head with hair
Long beautiful hair ♪
- Tom, come back here.
The Mads are calling.
- What.
- Sail on, Servo.
I love a robot with panache.
- Yeah, right, whatever.
Well Joel,
everyone knows that design
is the combination
of two separate elements.
That's why
we've taken interior design,
meshed it with household pests,
and come up with something
we like to call
decorator roaches.
- Yes, roaches.
Fashions come and go,
but roaches are forever.
Our invention exchange
this week is, swatch roaches.
Now, for you,
southwest enthusiasts,
we have this little number
I like to call La Cucaracha.
[Laughs]
Get it?
Of course you do.
And for the sports enthusiast
in your life,
we have the 49ers roach
complete with colors.
And over here we have
the Peter Max roach.
- Ay, I have found a roach
we haven't categorized yet.
Purple, and gold,
and it's got
a little skimpy mustache on it.
- My God, you found
the Prince roach!
Frank, sign him up
for penny of the month club.
Say, I didn't catch your name.
- Uh, Steve.
Steve Reeves.
- Steve Reeves?
Steve Hercules Reeves?
Wow!
- Frank...
- Say, you're not gonna
believe this.
Talk about serendipitous
experiences,
we're showing
one of your movies today.
- Nuh-uh.
- Yuh-huh.
- Oh, that's great.
I'm glad you're all happy
about the Prince roach.
Look, I'm just gonna
cut out of here,
I'll bill you for all the work,
alright?
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Uh, Joel? Why don't you go on
with your invention exchange.
- God.
Well sirs, our invention
exchange is the Steve-O-Meter.
- No relation to Steve Reeves.
- Right.
Well, Steve Allen,
as you know,
is the author of over 300 books
of short stories.
- Over 4,000 pop songs.
- The board game,
"Blow Your Own Horn."
- Yeah, there's so many things
that Steve Allen is thought of,
that's why we came up
with the Steve-O-Meter.
- There is the world
that is known,
there is the unknown,
and there is what Steve knows.
- Right, exactly.
So, what you do is
if you thought of a new idea,
you run the Steve-O-Meter
over it,
and if it buzzes, well,
Steve's already thought of it.
What have you
got for us here, Crow?
- Okay. It's an extremely
simple and economical
desalinization
process for seawater.
- Oh, okay. Let's run
the Steve-O-Meter over it.
[Beeping]
- Oh, no...
- Drats!
- He's thought of it already.
- Well, how about this, Joel?
A series of novels
about me and Jane Meadows
solving murders together?
[BEEPING]
- Oh, sorry.
- How does it do that?
- Well, here's
my invention, my idea.
It's the Steve-O-Meter,
I'll just run the Steve-O-Meter
over the Steve-O-Meter and...
[Beeping]
Oh no!
He's thought of that too!
He's everywhere!
ALL:
- That's so great, Steve.
I really appreciate that.
You are one cool breed of cat,
let me tell you.
Eh, Steve,
check this out, huh?
Roach burial, huh?
- Why, you little...
[Grunts]
[Moaning]
- Tell them about the movie.
- Oh, alright.
This is the first or second?
- Second.
- This is the second movie
that I did,
"Hercules Unchained."
A much younger Steve Reeves.
And let me tell you,
on this set,
I toasted
more than one brain cell,
if you know
what I'm saying.
[Groaning]
- Push the button.
- Oh, right.
Push the button.
Here you go.
ALL:
Movie sign?
Steve Allen
thought of that too!
[Screaming]
[♪♪♪]
Crow:
[Humming]
TOM:
Oh, interesting.
Hmm.
JOEL:
Lux Films, for dishes.
TOM:
Viva la company.
[Chuckles]
CROW:
Steve Reeves and the Vandellas.
JOEL:
Steve Allen thought of that.
CROW:
Oh.
TOM:
Unchained Hercules,
♪ Oh Hercules my darling ♪
CROW:
That-- uh, did that happen?
JOEL:
Oh, get technical.
TOM:
And Levoras and angina
by Pepitone.
[All humming with soundtrack]
TOM:
♪ Silvia's mother said... ♪
JOEL:
Quiet, Dr. Hook.
TOM:
Oh.
CROW:
More sunscreen
in aisle seven, sir.
TOM:
Oh, I know this movie.
It's "White Men Can't Row."
JOEL:
Hey, you guys, bad news.
The captain
wants to water ski.
My dad told me that one.
TOM: That's pretty funny.
JOEL: It's funny.
TOM:
Can I use that.
CROW:
Hey, if you like Giorgio,
you'll love Primo.
TOM:
♪ Sylvia... ♪
JOEL:
Stop it.
TOM:
Sylvia.
CROW:
I'm long.
[Tom humming]
CROW:
If you think he's long, try me.
Longest.
TOM:
Long, longer, longest.
CROW:
How fast you figure
we're going, Bob?
JOEL:
Strike a pose.
[WHISPERS]
Nothing to it.
CROW:
I'm tied to the mast.
TOM:
Frankie Avalon
in slave ship bingo.
Whoa.
JOEL: Oar Folkjokeopus.
TOM:
Oh, I was wondering
where that came from.
- Raise the oars, men!
TOM:
Raise High
the Roofbeam Carpenter!
Bravo Bava.
CROW:
This movie brought to you
by the letters A, B, and C.
[All commentators
garbled speech to each other]
- Lower the anchor!
JOEL:
Why don't you do
anything around here?
[Tom chuckles]
CROW:
Hey, that's the laundry!
TOM: [GROANS]
Bye, Mr. Hoffa.
[Chuckles]
JOEL:
Hey.
[Trumpet]
[Tom imitates trumpet]
JOEL:
Next week on Genesis II.
TOM:
It's wagon train.
NARRATOR:
This is the land of Attica.
ALL:
Attica! Attica! Attica!
NARRATOR:
What new adventures await
Hercules in this,
his native land?
JOEL:
I get the feeling
you're gonna tell us.
NARRATOR:
...he set out alone.
And now he returns
with Iole, his bride.
CROW:
Hey, stop feeding my bride.
NARRATOR:
Accompanying Hercules and Iole
to the city of Thebes
will be the young Ulysses,
son of Laertes.
[Tom humming]
Hey, I'm still in here!
NARRATOR:
...bid farewell to their
comrades who have shared
their dangerous adventures
of the last two years.
ALL:
Farewell, comrades.
NARRATOR:
...dauntless pilot
of the Argonauts.
TOM:
And master of knots.
CROW:
Thinks he looks like
Walter Matthau.
NARRATOR:
Laertes,
the restless ruler of Ithaca...
JOEL:
Goes through a lot
of skin bronzer.
NARRATOR:
Argo,
who constructed the ship
that's served them all so well.
- You bring to Thebes
the most beautiful girl
in... [indistinct]
CROW:
Thank you, Feces.
TOM:
Certainly, Hideous.
- I'd love to see if anyone
can put him in chains.
[All commentators
groaning and whistling]
- I ask you this one favor.
Because I feel
your judgment is mature.
JOEL:
Is the horse talking?
- Ulysses is only a child
who thinks he's a man...
[Tom makes baby sounds]
- I think he knows.
You'll behave?
TOM:
Jeff Goldblum!
- ...it's only father.
- Now, you listen to me.
- Excuse me,
but you don't have to worry.
- There, you see?
He has no respect.
- What are these?
TOM:
Hey, no respect.
Herodicus Dangerfieldicus.
- ...use one of these.
Carefully tie a message
to the leg of a pigeon
and he'll bring it to me.
- But what are you doing
with my pigeons here?
A present, they were hers,
Penelope got them at Samos.
- That's true.
And they'll always fly back
to Ithaca
no matter
where you release them.
CROW:
What if you release them
in Ithaca?
- ...discover that these pigeons
can transport the news
quicker than we can,
you will see
that the world
will be very different.
- It's only that
most of us feel
your pigeons are better to eat.
[Laughing]
- Farewell, Hercules.
TOM:
I don't get it.
- Take care of my son.
- Is it my wife
you're interested in too, or me?
Here she is.
JOEL:
Let's bring her out again.
[All commentators
whistling and clapping]
- Come, help me up.
- Oh, I almost forgot.
TOM:
Underwear.
You need it.
- This lute,
it's from Orpheus.
- Who's that for?
- If you expect to play
the lute with those hands.
[Laughing]
It's for your wife.
TOM:
Liar, liar, lutes on fire.
[Chuckles]
JOEL:
Looks like a giant egg cutter.
TOM:
I was gonna read
on the trip, but...
- Please thank him for me.
- Of course.
TOM:
Throw this in the box marked
garage sale.
- Farewell, Ulysses.
Heed the teachings of Hercules
because one day you will...
- Goodbye, Father.
CROW:
I know, so I can
get into a good school.
- Hurry, Hercules,
otherwise we'll all be crying.
[Tom crying]
- Be careful, my son.
- I will, Father!
JOEL:
Boy, it sure would be hard
to leave all that, huh?
TOM:
Have fun storming the castle,
to thine own self be true,
watch out for that curve, whoa!
CROW:
The high Chaparral.
TOM:
♪ Bum bum bum ♪
ALL COMMENTATORS:
♪ Here comes the king ♪
♪ Here comes the
King wu whoa wu... ♪
JOEL:
♪ Here comes... ♪
[Tom chuckles]
CROW:
♪ Oh ho the Wells Fargo ♪
Come on, everybody!
♪ Oh ho the Wells-- ♪
Aw. Mean.
- Tomorrow we'll see
the city of Thebes.
JOEL:
Oh, big deal, dad.
- We can tell him
all about it.
We want you to know that
we've been listening to you.
We know that the king
is Oedipus...
- Who's a fine man.
- And as for Thebes,
it's tremendous.
All spacious and rich.
- And the stadium and the baths
and the palaces,
it must be heaven,
if you listen to Hercules.
TOM:
And the baths and the malls
and the baths and the...
- I don't know
what you're joking about.
TOM:
I don't get it.
- Now you'll see
what a real city's like.
Why, you'll hardly
believe your eyes.
JOEL:
They've got sports bars,
you know?
- ...courtesy
of the people alone.
JOEL:
And the baths!
TOM:
Hey.
Hmm?
- [indistinct] people,
bristling with anger.
CROW:
Who are those guys?
TOM:
Spartan jerks.
[Coughing]
- ...Thebans, and their manners
are most exquisite.
- They're Argives.
What are they doing in Attica?
CROW: A nickel.
- Why worry about it.
- The Argives are fighters.
They live on war.
They thrive on massacres.
- But wasn't their
commander a Theban?
Let's go a little faster.
- I'll show them!
CROW:
Do you want to go faster?
TOM:
Whoo!
- Hercules,
the ceremony you went through,
the bonds of matrimony,
now you're married.
So, drive carefully.
- I'm grateful, Ulysses,
thanks for the reminder.
CROW: But shut up.
- Ho.
Ho.
CROW:
Who you calling "ho?"
- So that's the way it is.
You're playing games with me?
Alright then, have your fun.
I want to rest.
TOM:
He ran out of body grease
and he gets all crabby.
- Huh! Huh!
CROW:
Conkacha.
- Go to sleep a bit.
CROW:
Gee, looks like
Poppin' Fresh muffins.
TOM:
All buttery.
JOEL:
He's talking to himself.
[Crow hums "smoke on the water"
by deep purple]
[Harp plays]
JOEL:
♪ In the jungle
The mighty jungle the... ♪
TOM:
♪ We all went down to Montreux ♪
- ♪ Love was in those eyes ♪
TOM:
♪ Hercules couldn't perform ♪
CROW:
Shut up about that.
TOM:
- ♪ 'Cause he's using steroids ♪
CROW:
I am not.
She's using
the Mel Bay method.
- ♪ Remain your words to me ♪
JOEL:
Thank you, next!
CROW:
Mrs. Partridge, mom-hmm.
- ♪ Tell me in the skylight
Last night... ♪
TOM:
Sounds like a Western.
- ♪ I was in your arms ♪
CROW:
Hey, this is a family show.
TOM:
Hey, the Herc is
trying to sleep back here.
- ♪ ...the evening star
I will walk... ♪
[All howling like wolves]
JOEL:
She's gonna crack her makeup.
- ♪ Just you and I
By the evening star ♪
CROW:
Think I'll fall on my spear,
heh heh.
[♪♪♪]
- Hey.
Hey!
Stop a moment, stranger.
JOEL:
Our we at grandma's?
- ...mine.
And no one passes through
this valley unless I say so,
and they pay a price.
CROW:
Anthony Quinn?
- ...this valley is Antaeus's.
And you'll do anything
because I say so.
TOM:
Ooo! Ooo, ow.
Alright, go ahead.
- Now, tell me.
Do you have any gold
hidden in the carriage?
And the first thing
I'll take are your horses,
so unharness them for me.
- Hercules?
Hercules?
- Oh, I want to sleep.
CROW:
Oh, thanks, Hercu-wuss.
- Come on, you. Get down,
I said I want the horses.
- You take advantage of us
just because you're Antaeus.
- And why not?
Just a boy and a lady.
Come on now!
Get down.
- I'll show you
what a boy can do.
CROW:
I can fly!
[Groans]
JOEL:
Nice recovery.
- Hercules, he'll kill him.
- I'm so sleepy,
I can't seem to keep awake.
TOM:
That'd be the definition
of sleepy.
- To my husband.
- And what's he doing?
- He was dozing.
- Dozing, was he?
I'll wake him up.
CROW:
I wouldn't do that.
- I know those sleepy husbands,
or is he just frightened?
- He might awaken
when he sees you.
- Husband!
JOEL:
You're my Valentine.
- Hey you, husband.
That's right, kiss your lady
goodbye and pass on.
I'm adopting the lady.
- Is that right?
- Yes, I'm taking her.
That's my pleasure.
I like her very much,
the lady.
- And what does
she say about that?
- She'd like a new husband,
like every woman.
[Laughs]
[Tom chuckles]
CROW:
Awkward moment.
- But Hercules...
Hercules!
TOM:
He makes Andre the Giant
look like Paul Newman.
- They all turn out
to be just like that.
Alright,
come on out and fight.
- A pleasure.
JOEL:
Ooo, ooo.
TOM:
What would happen
if he really hit him.
JOEL:
Why is he wearing a bathmat?
- Maybe the next time
you'll treat me better.
Come on, let's be on our way.
TOM:
Well, break out
the chest grease.
[Laughs]
JOEL:
He always sees
the bright side of everything.
[Tom chuckling]
- You've got a tough skin.
- Hey!
[Grunting]
CROW:
Lambada, the Forbidden Dance.
TOM:
You know, I had a dream
like this once.
JOEL:
Watch it,
I'm wearing my retainer.
TOM:
Lower...
[GRUNTS]
You got it, ah.
Chiropractors.
[Heavy breathing]
[Grunts]
[Tom imitates grunting]
JOEL:
I saw Lucy do this
to Mr. Mooney once.
CROW:
Oh! I fell on my keys.
TOM:
Who knows, is this a half nelson
or a full nelson?
CROW:
Uh, looks like a Ricky Nelson.
JOEL:
No, it's his kids,
it's just Nelson.
CROW:
What scares me
is they don't have showers.
JOEL:
Okay, you can have me.
I give up.
[Grunting]
TOM:
Rondo Hatton!
JOEL:
You know Rondo's good
'cause you can
slam him down hard.
See?
TOM:
Yeah, like that.
CROW:
Whoa, I see London,
I see France...
huh?
[Laughs]
TOM:
Oh.
CROW:
Snicker-snag on him,
dangle spit,
come on, Herc!
TOM:
I'd bite his nipple.
Any questions?
- Come on, Iole.
[Laughs]
TOM:
There he goes.
CROW:
Yeah, I wish he was on our side.
He seems really fun.
- He might be a god.
- I don't care if he's Pluto.
TOM:
Paul Pluto?
- I'm going to knock
that silly grin off his face
once and for all.
- The god of spice?
[TOM CHUCKLES]
[Grunting]
- I tell you, Hercules,
it must be Antaeus,
son of the earth goddess.
When he touches the ground,
he marshals his forces.
- So that's it?
Then I'll change
my way of fighting.
JOEL:
That's who he said he was.
- Let me down!
You just put me down
and you'll see!
TOM:
Put me down, put me down.
Mom, mom!
This isn't fun anymore.
Mom!
- I'll get even with you,
by the gods!
CROW:
I'll spank you.
- Put me down.
Let me down!
[Screaming]
CROW:
I've got tubes in my ears.
JOEL:
There.
Thanks, friend,
I haven't showered
since Zeus was a pup.
- ...but one day
you'll have to pass through
my valley again!
CROW:
Not after they build
the interstate.
TOM:
"The Virginian",
staring James Drury.
Brought to you by Nabisco.
[Imitates clock ticking]
TOM: [WOMAN"S VOICE]
Oh, thanks for beating up
Antaeus,
I really didn't want
to be his wife.
- Just a little way further.
CROW:
There's a gas station.
- I hope we'll be able
to rest there.
- I know this forest
very well.
Why shouldn't we,
it's quiet here.
They say the gates
to the inferno
are hidden among its trees.
TOM:
On Broadway.
- But Hercules, look!
JOEL:
Oh, they're tailgating up ahead.
It must be a Packard game.
- It's the first time
I ever saw anyone here.
TOM:
Everybody's making out here.
- Oh, I'm getting wet.
- Hurry then.
CROW:
He's putting a car cover
on a horse?
- Stop, what do you want?
- Let her alone.
She's come to keep us company.
[TOM CHUCKLES]
- You'll soon find out.
Don't worry.
- Now look at that.
She's beginning to fight.
I'd better tame you.
[Tom grunting]
JOEL:
Well, he's bald.
CROW:
Not raining there.
TOM:
I'm with the big guy, sorry.
JOEL:
Edward Arnold?
- But wasn't that Hercules?
CROW:
He's shorter than his pictures.
[Laughing]
JOEL:
They're giddy with violence.
TOM:
And then we ducked
into a little café.
- Be quiet.
- You went to... [indistinct]
my own children
plotted to steal my kingdom
and share it between you.
CROW:
Mr. Hoyle, you're late.
- You and your brother have
driven me out of my kingdom.
Only here can I find asylum.
And here I shall die.
- Oedipus...
JOEL:
Cut! Cut.
Hercules, please.
- I know that voice.
It recalls a time in my life
when I was happier.
CROW:
Look, it's me, Hercules.
[Coughing]
I came at a bad time, didn't I?
- To me, you are
still the faithful Hercules.
- What are you doing here?
JOEL:
I'm Ralph Richardson.
- You're Polynices .
CROW:
I remember you from the gym.
- It was not up to me.
My son thought it better
I renounce the throne,
and so at last I did,
so that he and his brother
might rule.
CROW:
And do they write? No.
- ...the throne
to his brother.
But now Polynices tells me
that the year is up.
JOEL:
The god of exposition.
- ...it's my turn now
and it's plain to see
just what his brother
wants to do.
TOM:
It's my turn!
- ...he won't
cede to his brother.
He promised to do so,
but now that his year is up,
he has driven his brother away.
JOEL:
In this new car!
[Tom and crow cheering]
- Just politeness.
- I am not going
to be deceived.
I noticed what he wants,
to get and keep the throne
with the help of the Argives.
The throne
carries only tragedy.
It can bring no happiness.
And your city will fall
between these two brothers.
CROW:
So, what I'm hearing here,
Polynices,
is you're angry
with your father, hmm?
- ...and it's men
will be slain...
JOEL: Let's go.
- ...and its women,
so long as
these two ambitious rulers
get what they want now.
- Now, listen to me, Polynices,
I've known you
since you were a child,
and I respect your father.
Otherwise, I would exact
justice for Thebes.
CROW:
Crossfire, on the left,
Hercules!
- ...I'll go to your brother
and try to convince him
to respect the pact you made.
JOEL:
Pact shmact.
- ...noble thought
that you have, Hercules.
TOM:
On paper.
- ...my sons
will listen to no one.
- But Thebes is my city.
Will you spare people
this bloodshed?
JOEL:
And we built this city
on rock and roll!
- ...madness of these men,
or I'll believe that I...
ALL COMMENTATORS:
Hercules...
- ...Hercules,
am deserted by the gods!
JOEL:
Echo, echo, echo...
- Well, Polynices...
CROW:
Well, I can give you
a small part in the chorus,
but that's all.
TOM:
He can pass the pencil test, eh.
- If it's better.
Go Eteocles, go on.
I grant you six days
to let me know
if you can make peace.
- At the end of those six days,
we'll march our army
against the Thebans.
- ♪ Heading out to
Eden yeah brother ♪
- Tom, consider the grape.
- Oh, I will.
- So delicate.
So firm.
[Gasping]
- You guys, I don't see why
I have to be the one
to peel these grapes.
You know, it's really
kind of hard.
- And he calls
himself a hedonist.
[Laughing]
- Well, you know what?
I think it's great
that Gypsy built this set
and made these costumes for us
just so she could put on a show.
You guys should do
something like that.
- You know, you're right.
Starting right now,
I'm gonna roll over
and eat more grapes.
- Ah.
- Oh, here she comes.
She's beautiful.
- Hey, looking good, Gypsy.
- Thank you.
And now
for a little song in G.
[Clears throat]
♪ Last night... ♪
- Her gown is like
a beautiful breeze.
- ♪ Last night... ♪
♪ Last night... ♪
- So, what's
she supposed to be, Joel?
- I'm the Hellenistic ideal.
- ♪ Last night... ♪
- You know, folks,
you just don't hear
music like that anymore.
- You know, folks,
I have a feeling
this is gonna go on like this,
so why don't you
run on ahead to the commercial.
We'll catch up...
- ♪ Last night I couldn't
Get to sleep at all... ♪
- Hey, Joel?
Am I the only one that notices
I'm not eating a grape?
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
That was good.
TOM:
[indistinct].
- Welcome to my house,
Eteocles.
CROW:
Two words, Hercules,
"French doors."
- ...the lady with you?
- No,
Ulysses will come with me.
CROW:
Same thing.
- Ulysses?
Ulysses, now who is he?
- Ulysses, son of Laertes,
King of Ithaca.
- A king without soldiers?
I'm not interested.
Take this.
TOM:
Put it where
the sun don't shine.
- You can tell my brother
this.
From now on,
what he asks I will do.
JOEL:
You've been lifting,
what's your max?
- That's what
you're here for, isn't it?
And tomorrow morning,
I'll send servants,
goods, and provisions.
CROW:
And lawyers, guns and money.
- If you live alone
here in Thebes,
you'll grow impatient.
TOM:
Need a roommate?
- Thank you.
- I'll guard Iole,
'til he gets home.
- Aw, then I'm certain
she'll be alright.
CROW: Ouch.
JOEL: Grrr.
- Creon is the purest and most
intelligent man in Thebes.
TOM:
And Creon's nontoxic.
- ...in his way.
I bid you goodbye.
[Laughs]
CROW:
Everyone's a comedian.
JOEL:
Well, guess it's
catch as catch can.
TOM:
Next week, on Alias,
Hercules and Ulysses.
CROW:
Ow, ow, ow...
TOM:
Industry! Big and bold.
JOEL:
♪ We are riding horses
We are fancy free friend ♪
CROW:
And that's when I won
first prize at the fair.
TOM:
Let me out of this cage,
oh, you're murdering me.
[Cries]
JOEL:
Well, we must be there,
the music's dying down now.
CROW:
Oh, ho ho.
What a fun day.
TOM:
What, cotton?
JOEL:
Meanwhile, Flabius,
son of Magor,
is feuding with Crylon.
TOM:
I'm pretty sure
this is a Star Trek set.
CROW:
Looks like
a Maxfield Parish painting.
TOM:
Kinda.
- Something
about this place...
TOM:
Reminds me of Appleton.
- Look! I'm hungry.
CROW:
Listen, it's cold.
- And make sure
and take good aim.
And remember...
- The distance,
the force of the wind,
the speed of the target...
JOEL:
Hey, Herc's trying sidesaddle,
check it out.
- Well said.
I'll go start the fire up.
And don't come
back empty handed.
TOM:
Nature abhors a vacuum.
CROW:
Well, that bird'll be
in the next county by now.
VOICE:
These are waters
of forgetfulness.
JOEL:
Wilber, no!
VOICE:
Those who drink
of them will forget all.
[Horse whinnies]
CROW:
He's right, you know?
JOEL:
Duh, what was that?
Who do I belong to?
What planet am I on?
Duh, I forgot how
to breathe, mmm...
CROW:
I've forgotten everything
but I can't seem to get
afternoon delight
out of my mind.
♪ Skyrockets in flight... ♪
[Woman's voice singing]
TOM:
Do I hear Dorothy Lamour?
JOEL:
Hardly any animals were hurt
in the making of this movie.
- It's a fine one.
CROW:
Mr. Grinch.
TOM: [GRUNTING]
Hey Ulysses,
Hercules drank from
the fountain of forgetfulness,
pass it on.
Bye, gotta go, see ya.
- Where are they going?
JOEL:
We're going to
Dayton's Warehouse Sale!
CROW:
It's so crunchy,
you'll do a triple take.
TOM:
Nice [indistinct] work,
sounds like he's running
on a gym floor.
CROW:
Oh no, oh no it's the--
it's the thing!
TOM:
No!
JOEL:
You know, I just know
there's a hot chick
around here somewhere.
TOM:
Let's see, is it live
or is it Memorex?
I've forgotten.
- Iole!
- What's happening?
CROW:
Are you having
one of your episodes?
Put a wallet under my tongue.
TOM:
What's a wallet?
- Where are you Iole?
- Hercules, what's the matter?
- Iole,
can't you hear her voice?
Can't you hear it?
CROW:
It's difficult.
TOM:
No, it's not difficult...
- But I don't hear anyone.
CROW:
I think it's from Anything Goes.
- Hercules, look at me,
it's Ulysses.
Hercules, listen to me.
Hercules!
CROW:
Wow, he didn't forget
how to be rude, now did he?
Well, this is as good
a place as any.
You know what they say,
you can only rent
the waters of forgetfulness.
[Chuckles]
Oh yeah.
JOEL:
Look, I told you,
truffles, right?
I'm right every time.
CROW:
Maybe it's me.
JOEL:
James Brolin.
CROW:
You really are strong.
TOM:
I forgot how my muscles work.
CROW:
Now I can pose them
in funny positions.
[Giggles]
TOM:
Mmm?
Blood Sweat and Tears?
[Imitates horn music]
CROW:
Just playing Narcissus here.
TOM:
And Goldman?
JOEL:
Ulysses, it's the waters
of forgetfulness,
now his chest
won't remember a thing!
TOM:
Alright, we're out of time,
could somebody here dial IX-I-I?
[Crow imitates siren]
Alright, we're the ambulance,
pretty much.
- Who are you?
- Uh...
JOEL:
It's Sal Mineo.
- [indistinct]
[Groaning]
- This one
is taking no chances,
traveling alone
with a deaf mute.
CROW:
Oh, I'm glad you think
I'm a deaf mute-- oh nuts.
- And you, come along.
Come on.
CROW: My hine-der.
[Groaning]
TOM:
It sounds like a...
Oh, forget it.
[Humming]
It sounds like
the flower drum song
all of a sudden.
CROW:
Oh, I did not need to see that.
TOM:
Uh, my eye.
♪ Flying eye... ♪
CROW:
The mighty [indistinct].
We're fine now.
TOM:
James A Michener's Adventures--
oh, you know the drill.
[All talking at once]
JOEL:
Sleepover, huh?
I see.
CROW:
I am beat.
TOM:
I like this.
Got it in a seven and a half.
- Better see...
JOEL:
Rachael Ward?
- ...I'll test him.
We'll know
if he's deaf or not.
TOM:
Uh-oh, let's see here.
[Clears throat]
So, I'm a big Marley Matlin fan,
how about you?
Boy, I sure loved
the Miracle Worker.
- Do you still have any doubts?
- I almost let
a yelp for him myself!
[Yammerings of agreement]
TOM:
My scalp actually tingles, sir!
CROW:
Good work. sir!
Hey. I can hear the ocean.
Oh, it is the ocean.
JOEL:
Evan Rood, the Early Years.
TOM:
Jeez, how deeply did he drink
from the waters
of forgetfulness?
CROW:
Hey, thanks for helping me
move Hercules this weekend.
I got beer and pizza for ya.
JOEL:
♪ It's a Sealy Posturepedic
Morning ya ♪
CROW:
Aw, they're gonna dump him
on his parent's steps.
JOEL:
Aw, that's sad.
TOM:
Mmm?
Oh, they're taking him
to the Tiki Room,
he'll be fine.
ALL:
♪ Oh-we-oh-we-oh-oh ♪
CROW:
Shoot! I'm outta triple sec.
- [indistinct]
...they're arriving.
[All commentators singing]
- Yes Grey Queen, they're here.
CROW:
Really? You think I'm grey?
- Don't desert me, please?
Don't desert me.
TOM:
I was just going
to go to the bathroom.
Talk about abandonment issues.
CROW:
Turn the fan on!
Oh, sorry.
TOM:
This place is even cooler
than Roda's apartment, huh?
JOEL:
This World Italy!
CROW:
Postage due on this one.
TOM:
Inspect before you sign.
- Hercules, the Theban,
your Highness.
TOM:
I gathered, hmm.
- This is his servant,
just a poor deaf mute.
[All talking at once]
- Listen to me.
- Take him away.
TOM:
I just love Italian beef,
mmm.
- Omphale...
JOEL:
Pig Latin?
- You told me you love me!
Save me, Omphale!
Help me!
CROW:
Help me, Spock, help me.
TOM:
Yeah, we know.
Es tu Brute, yeah.
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
Blood Sugar Sex Magik, mmm.
- There's something
I'd like to ask you.
TOM:
Is that a Jansen suit
you're wearing?
- And what would
you like to ask me?
- What's happened to me?
I don't remember anything.
TOM:
Except my scout number.
- Not even who I am.
- And is that so important?
JOEL:
Well, I'm pretty sure
I got a paycheck coming.
- I can't remember anything.
TOM:
Oh, hi, Dave.
- Do you know this boy?
- Why?
- Think hard.
TOM:
I can't, it hurts.
- I've never seen him before.
JOEL:
I was in Austria
during the war.
TOM:
Okay, bye.
- Come sit beside me.
CROW:
Move your big old leg.
TOM:
♪ Take the ribbon
From my hair ♪
- Who is that boy?
- Your servant.
CROW:
You win the crazy award.
- My servant?
- Yes.
- I swear by the gods that I...
- You want me to believe
that you can't remember?
That you're the king
of this land?
That you're my husband?
CROW:
So take out the garbage.
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
So, those are his daughters
then, huh?
CROW:
There will be no seating
until the first intermission.
JOEL:
Team Reebok.
TOM:
This is our interpretation
of spring.
CROW:
Thanks for the good seats.
TOM:
You take that two drink minimum
seriously,
don't you?
JOEL:
Jesse?
Now Jerome.
TOM:
Cassie?
CROW:
Jazz hands, jazz hands!
TOM:
Three and four
and step and turn and...
Ladies and gentleman,
Danny Terrio!
JOEL:
Oh, this must be headliner.
TOM:
Oh boy.
I hope she's in a body stocking.
JOEL:
Ordinary pantyhose are okay
under funky clothes
but gentlemen prefer Hanes.
CROW:
Ooo.
[Tom imitates music]
All snaky like.
CROW: Where'd she go?
TOM: Huh? Huh?
CROW:
Oh, there she is.
TOM:
Oh, like who can't do that?
CROW:
Oh, I'm standing on my head.
Could somebody help me?
TOM:
So, does this thing
heat up at all?
JOEL:
Hey, this is not
my beautiful house.
This is not my beautiful wife.
How did I get here?
CROW:
Ah, the chicken dance,
very nice.
JOEL:
That's what I did in my act.
CROW:
Hey, wait a minute.
Her skin has a zipper.
TOM:
Ooo.
ALL:
Timber!
JOEL:
Let's see, it snowed real bad
and we got snowed in
and Murray had to stay over,
and then...
CROW:
This is jogging my memory.
TOM:
It's jogging something.
[Chuckles]
- Anyway, I like the idea
of being a king.
By the way, what's my name?
JOEL:
Who's my daddy?
Was he rich,
was he rich like me?
- Nothing,
it's just if you called me...
- To me, your name is love.
CROW:
Buddy Love?
- Ha ha. I'm beginning
to like this place.
- And me.
TOM:
Eh, you I can take or leave.
- ...most of all.
JOEL:
Hey, 2,000 years,
that'll be worth something.
TOM:
What are you doing?
Ooo, you taste like Diogenes.
What're they up to, Joel?
CROW:
Uh, let's pack it up, girls.
Our work here is finished.
TOM: Tada.
CROW: Mmm, bless this mess?
Huh.
TOM:
Hey, this is the girl's dorm.
JOEL:
Aw, this is really cute, Karen,
can I borrow it sometime?
CROW:
Hey, all the boys
have to register
at the front desk.
- What's in the bottom
of the chest?
Does it mean anything
for you or Hercules?
CROW:
What's that supposed to mean?
- Will you be still?
JOEL:
Gonna cry now, baby?
- When is he coming?
- He's only been gone
about three days.
- Because of this treaty,
you know.
They need time.
You can't settle them
right away.
- Yes, I see. If he's delayed,
it's only logical.
But I feel so anxious
when I don't hear.
JOEL:
We should have at least
gotten a pigeon by now.
- I'll stay
only until tomorrow morning
and then I'll go to see
if I can locate him.
TOM:
I'll call the finder
of lost loves.
CROW:
All of a sudden
it's paint your wagon.
All:
[Singing "one tin soldier"]
♪ Peace on earth
Was all it said... ♪
TOM: [CLAPPING]
Do do do!
CROW:
Hey, I can see
my house from here.
TOM:
Bird loves, woo!
CROW:
I thought I saw Ulythes...
I did, I did see Ulythes.
TOM:
Hey, you guys wait here.
JOEL:
I was just doing the dishes.
[Hums]
- Come on, now.
You're going to work, now!
JOEL:
I gotta finish
these dishes first.
TOM:
You're... hurting...
- My boy, I've discovered
something very important.
TOM:
This really bugs me.
- Up to now, I've been making
one big mistake.
CROW:
Hey, is he turtle waxing him?
- And stay awake at night.
Otherwise you'll lose
the best part of your life.
JOEL:
I can see you've been real--
really thinking deep here, sir.
TOM:
Hey, it's Ting.
You know that's hard
to find around here.
- Is it prepared?
CROW:
Mmm, dinner, Herc.
- Ah, yes.
The night was made for love.
JOEL:
And Michelob.
- The sun out there
dulls the senses.
Enough.
I'm hungry.
TOM:
Well, I think you just
insulted the waitress.
- Ha ha.
What a life.
You wake up in the morning
without a care in the world
and nothing to do.
CROW:
Just like collecting
unemployment checks.
TOM:
What the heck ya doing there?
- Clumsy!
It looks like
you did it on purpose.
JOEL:
Shhh, let's play charades.
CROW:
Okay, I'll go along.
ALL COMMENTATORS:
Look to the left,
look to the right,
stand up, sit down,
and fight fight fight!
CROW:
This is the
fountain of dorkiness.
TOM:
Eh, got any ketchup for this?
CROW:
Don't tell.
- You are Hercules.
ALL COMMENTATORS:
Thbbbt!
- What did you say?
TOM: I forgot already.
- Hercules.
TOM:
Uh-huh.
- Hercules?
What about Hercules?
- Iole.
- Go away.
I don't understand a thing.
TOM:
Mmm-hmm.
- Iole, your marriage,
Eteocles,
Polynises, the message...
TOM:
Uh, uh, things you'd say
to Socrates.
- Bend it.
If you can't,
you'll convince me.
CROW:
If you can, you're Uri Geller.
JOEL:
You're lucky
I'm in a good mood, Ulysses.
[Grunting]
CROW:
Oh, rats. I can't bend it.
Guess I have to stay here
with all the nymphs.
TOM:
Hit the road, Pedro.
Oh, hi, Herc.
[Crow whistles]
[Tom imitates horn music]
- Good morning.
- Did you sleep well last night?
- Wonderfully.
I dreamt of ya.
- And I'm flattered.
CROW:
And flattery will
get you everywhere.
TOM:
Eh, old ball and chain.
[Chuckles]
JOEL:
So, what's on the slate today?
Eatin' and lovin', huh?
- Somehow, I recall
that you had a different face.
JOEL:
Yeah, it was Phyllis Diller's,
I had to return it.
- No. Just different.
Blonde hair, sweet smile.
JOEL:
Hair growing out of your wart.
- So you've begun to betray me
in your dreams.
- Aren't you afraid that somehow
we'll displease the fates,
and they'll take
their revenge on us?
TOM:
I try not to think about it.
So, anyway.
JOEL:
Uh, guys? Guys...
- I don't want to talk
about sad things
when I'm so happy.
CROW:
But they're--
something's gonna--
Joel, what are they...
TOM:
What they gonna...
[♪♪♪]
VOICE ON PA:
This is
the water of forgetfulness.
Those who drink
of it will forget all.
- Say, who manufactures
the water of forgetfulness,
anyway?
- Oh, it says
here on the bottle...
Mendota Springs, makers
of the water of forgetfulness
since-- uh-oh--
let me think--
oh, it's on the tip
of my tongue-- when was it?
VOICE ON PA:
This is the carob shake
of pretentiousness.
- Ooo, let me try that.
VOICE ON PA:
Those who drink of it will
join theater companies.
- Yeah, you know, I'm doing
an anti-Columbus thing
down at the heart of
the Meat Puppet Beast Theater.
Yeah, it's a real opportunity
for me to stretch.
- Hey, Joel?
That cup looks like
it's from Dairy Queen.
Can I have some?
- Mmm-hmm.
VOICE ON PA:
This is the blizzard
of loneliness.
Those who drink off it
will sit on the beach wearing
long pants and black socks
and look for change in the sand
with a metal detector.
- I found a quarter!
- Hey, who wants gum?
ALL: I do, I do!
- Here.
VOICE ON PA:
You're eating the fruit
striped gum of civility.
Those who chew it
will get a civil service job
with good benefits.
- Yup, thanks to the fruit
stripe gum of civility,
I gotta a good
dental plan now.
Ironic, huh?
VOICE ON PA:
You are eating
the green bean and French onion
casserole of happiness.
Those who eat off it
will find the serenity
that only a hot dish can bring.
- Oh, you know, I really,
really love this stuff.
It's so nutritious
and it's so good for you
and I love my location,
it's so conveniently located.
What with the [indistinct]
and dinner theater
and the new high school.
And oh, the Elks Lodge
puts on a wonderful fish fry
every weekend.
And we're right next
to the chain of lakes.
And we've got movie sign,
and they do the big Chatakwa
show every summer,
and they've got movie sign...
ALL:
Movie sign?
[Yelling]
TOM:
That dish is filling, isn't it?
JOEL AND CROW:
Oh, yes. So good.
CROW:
Hey, Peter, Paul, and Mary.
- And where did they
find the princess?
TOM:
The Personals.
- Just planning to run away
because
she couldn't stand Thebes,
and she wanted to rejoin
her husband.
CROW:
Walk this way.
Full stop.
- Did you,
did you hear from Hercules?
CROW:
Well, just a message
on my machine.
- ...he's away and all I've done
was wait here alone.
And if I did run away,
it was only that,
I beg you
to let me go to Hercules.
JOEL:
And let me smoke in my room.
- Reunited under the tender care
of my brother Polynises.
- I don't see what you mean,
sire.
- Well, it's not her fault,
Eteocles.
And why blame Hercules?
Don't you see?
If you let them go
to each other, then...
TOM:
Stop yelling!
Why is everyone yelling!
- You talk to me
as if I'm prepared
to take leave of my senses.
Take the woman away.
- But they're posing
for the Primo Beer can.
TOM AND CROW:
Cool.
- But that's unjust, inhuman.
- I shall now arrest
any and all Thebans
suspected
of plotting with Polynises.
Arrest them all!
JOEL: They left, sir.
- With their goods,
and families, and servants.
JOEL:
Can't we just arrest
everyone in red?
- You all pretend
that you want justice.
That nobody Hercules
and my friends here at court.
TOM:
God!
- Creon will be my example.
TOM:
What about [indistinct]?
[All commentators mumbling]
CROW:
Made ya look, ha ha.
TOM:
And now, a journey
through the lymph nodes.
JOEL:
You mean nymph loads.
TOM:
Oh.
CROW:
Hey.
Oh, working on
a new filing system.
[Laughs]
Alright.
TOM:
Oh, oh.
[Imitates snoring sound]
- Wake up,
it's time to go to work.
Get out of bed now.
CROW:
I can't hear you,
I'm sleeping...
in death.
- Get up now, it's late.
Your master's waiting
for his massage.
JOEL:
At two in the morning?
TOM:
Massage this, you cretin.
I mean, cratin.
CROW:
Creon will be played
by the bassoon.
[Tom humming]
CROW:
What the heck is going on here?
ALL: [ALONG WITH SOUNDTRACK]
Dum dum dum...
CROW:
Oh yeah, like no one's
gonna notice
the string on the lock.
JOEL:
It's a Hercules
power wrist band.
CROW:
Nice.
JOEL: [WHISPERING]
Real nice, fix it up good.
CROW:
Coming, mom.
TOM:
Ooo, yeah.
Big old jelly donut, oh.
CROW:
You are nuttier than
an outhouse rat, you know that?
- That's the second time
you knocked over my goblet.
CROW:
How would he remember that?
- I do it for you, Hercules.
- Why is it you keep on
calling me Hercules?
JOEL:
You know my name is Todd.
TOM:
Mmm, really tore through
those bear claws, didn't you?
- ...I've heard
that name before.
- You'll see.
Soon you'll remember.
CROW:
Just look at
your chariot license.
- Too complicated
to explain to you now.
I beg you to avoid
drinking that water,
then you'll recover your memory
and soon
we'll be able to escape.
JOEL:
Escape from this, why?
- Isn't this your native land?
TOM:
Uh, Herc, I think you're getting
your appointments
mixed up there.
- ...comrades. We were
captured and brought here.
I tell you that
we must get out of here.
What I saw was so terrible.
JOEL:
Curly Sue?
- You see, during the day,
they don't bother me.
At night, I'm put into a cell
and locked inside.
Yesterday, I was looking
for a means to get out.
CROW:
That's Dippity-Do.
- ...I saw a path
leading to a cave.
TOM:
Here, let me demonstrate,
into the woods,
into the woods.
JOEL:
Dad?
CROW:
It's not that scary.
Well, maybe.
TOM:
Ooo, it's Kim Cattrall.
CROW:
It is scary.
JOEL:
Nice skort.
TOM:
Cute.
CROW:
Sir, please don't
touch the exhibit, please.
TOM:
Ya!
And then I came to
another passage and...
CROW:
It's Madame Tussaud.
[Joel screams]
TOM:
Now just about that time I--
Are you listening to me? Good.
CROW:
Dante's Inferno--
Wait, this is a Disco Inferno.
TOM:
Suddenly, "Up With People"
showed up.
You meet 'em wherever
you're going.
JOEL:
Oh, hi, Ray, hi, Earl.
CROW:
It's like a cheap
"Temple of Doom" set.
Oh, cool.
Well, it's like a thing maker.
JOEL:
He's got Batman underoos on.
- You Egyptians
are truly so clever
that almost certainly
you'll find
the way
of even preserving life.
- Life is different.
We can't create
the soul of man.
- Still, it must be exciting,
your work.
CROW:
Look, I just told you
it's different.
- Just the man.
TOM:
Just the women now!
- ...they way he stands.
- When can we expect to
get to work on Hercules?
JOEL:
Well, let's see.
I've got an eight o'clock
and a 9:30 and a-- oh.
TOM:
Gotta go, bye.
Come on, girls.
JOEL:
Wait, wait, come back.
You forgot your free casket.
Wasn't this
a "Remington Steele" episode?
CROW:
I think so.
- I tremble with fear at what
she plans to do with us,
Hercules.
- Why should I believe you.
- I expected that.
TOM:
What's that supposed to mean?
- I'm going to ask the queen
to see if you're lying.
- Omphale
will be sure to deny it...
CROW:
Queen! Queen!
- She'll kill me, and then,
what will happen to you?
I prefer to be killed by you
rather than that way.
TOM:
Why, thank you.
- I promise you,
I won't speak anymore
about Hercules or Omphale.
TOM:
Eh.
JOEL:
Cripes, I am the Herc!
TOM:
Just set that anywhere, Herc,
yeah.
JOEL:
Hi, who are you?
TOM:
Hey, ya jerk,
you bent my lamp.
CROW:
No, you did.
TOM:
Did not.
There.
CROW:
It's still bent.
They're gonna be able to tell.
JOEL:
He's back.
[Yelling and laughing
hysterically]
TOM:
I'm cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs,
cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs.
CROW:
It's a little embarrassing.
[Laughing hysterically]
[Yells and laughs]
JOEL:
I can't believe I liked him.
CROW:
Geez, turning into Harpo.
TOM:
When Kennedys ruled Greece.
JOEL:
Uh-oh, Heather's dad
is here, guys.
[Tom imitating trumpet]
So now, what we've done
with Hercules
is minimized his large forehead
with this flower ring
and accentuate
his massive chest.
- Go away now.
I said leave me!
CROW:
I never get tired of that.
- No one ever dared
give an order in my presence.
JOEL:
No one else is the Herc-meister.
- Well,
it's only the first time.
TOM:
Hey, it's 9:30, honey.
CROW:
So, what are they doing?
JOEL:
Oh, wow.
TOM:
Mmm, he's Herc-ulicious.
CROW:
What're they up to Joel, hmm?
- You have a strange power
over me.
CROW:
Power of attorney.
- Whether it's love or not,
I don't know.
JOEL:
I don't think it is.
- ...all I want is
just to be with you.
- That's the way I like it.
TOM:
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
CROW:
Bet he says
that to all the queens.
TOM:
Uh, more gushy stuff.
JOEL:
Ricola?
- What was that?
CROW: It's my pager.
- ...landed on the island.
- Great Queen...
JOEL: Thanks.
- ...is waiting.
Laertes of Ithaca has
arrived with a small crew.
They want to stay here
several days.
They're waiting to present
their respects.
- Tell them to go away.
Why don't they sail
back to Ithaca?
We don't want visitors.
- But we have to receive them.
CROW:
Well, okay.
- It would be an offense,
a grave offense.
- And it is not
an offense to me?
To be abandoned?
TOM:
Oh, love Herc.
- I won't be far away.
I won't be gone long.
Just time enough
to pay my respects.
JOEL:
And the water bill.
CROW:
Well, it's not everybody
who gets to make out
at Cypress Gardens.
- Wait here for me.
I will not be gone long.
TOM:
Does it look like
I'm gonna get up
and do something?
CROW:
What's for lunch?
[Tom whistling]
Uh-oh.
- Go on, back to your cell.
[Grunting]
You know
what the orders are!
CROW:
Come on, show's over,
nothing to see here.
- The Aegean Sea has not been
gentle with us, great Queen.
JOEL:
I lost it like four times.
- ...perilous voyage
ahead of us.
TOM:
Yeah, boohoo.
- Excuse us, mighty Queen...
JOEL:
We boofed.
- ...all that you see here
is poor and modest.
Mercy and hospitality
are all that we ask.
TOM:
At the Helmsley Palace.
- ...express our
homage and goodwill...
TOM:
These are gifts?
Don't bother wrapping.
CROW:
Sorry about the old guy,
he comes with the package.
- Thank you, Laertes,
King of Ithaca.
TOM:
Mmm.
- I have already given orders
that you and your friends
will be taken to the best wing
of the palace.
TOM:
Yeah, I'll bet
it's by the ice machine.
- My men will
accompany you there.
JOEL:
Could your women accompany us?
- Our humble thanks to you.
TOM:
I thought our presentation
was pretty good,
how about you?
- You, what is your name,
young man?
JOEL:
My name is Mrs. Norman Maine.
- I had the feeling
we'd met somewhere before.
TOM:
I just have the feeling.
- While the others are taken
to their rooms,
stay a moment with me.
I would like to try
and remember where we met.
- I'm at your service.
JOEL:
She always goes
for the jock types.
- Wait, but I'm smart, really.
And I'm funny.
Ah, they never pick
the old guy.
JOEL:
Excuse me, I'm late for my 2:30.
- Hercules, what did you say?
- Hercules.
- You mean, you don't know me?
Tell me of Ulysses.
- Who are you?
ALL:
♪ Are you are you are you ♪
- That's not who he is.
- You're right, Omphale.
It's just because
both Hercules
and this man
are both gigantic.
But if you take another look
at this man,
then it's plain to see
in a moment
that we men were in error.
- But see here, Laertes,
Hercules face,
and his figure,
this couldn't be Hercules.
- Who is this Hercules?
A born fighter,
and the greatest man in Thebes.
JOEL:
And a hell of an engineer.
- What does he have
to do with me?
- Nothing.
Why, it's like water and wine.
It's bad to mix them.
JOEL:
Everybody's teasing me.
- Please go,
I'll see you later.
- Not later,
right this minute.
TOM:
Who are you?
And who are you?
Eh.
- I pray you to pardon me.
Please excuse us, and now,
we'll retire if we may.
CROW:
Oh, well, here's your gold watch
and your 401K.
TOM:
Miss Utah's a Rhodes Scholar
who wants world peace
and that special someone.
JOEL:
So, live around here much?
- I want to try this on.
CROW:
What does that
have to do with me?
- Pearls must have
contact with the flesh
before they take
their best sheen.
JOEL:
The closer she gets,
the weirder she looks. Ew.
- ...this necklace
will be much more beautiful.
[Joel groaning]
JOEL:
Great sunrise, let's go
have breakfast, fellas.
CROW:
It's the O'Cedar Man.
TOM:
Huh, must've blown a fuse.
JOEL:
Kinda makes you feel small,
doesn't it, Alvin.
- Now I'm ready
to begin action.
A man can only live
so long patiently.
CROW:
That's nice.
Ever thought of putting two
similar sentences together?
- The time is all gone.
Eteocles and Hercules
are conspiring
against me getting the throne.
TOM:
What, are you Jim Garrison?
- I'll be king yet.
And they, all they need to see
is this army coming.
Your army can
sweep under the Thebans.
CROW:
I hope one of the guys
has a dustpan hid.
- It'll be a surprise
for my friends down there.
- Certainly,
it will be a great thing
beating the Thebans.
The throne is there
and the riches of the city.
TOM:
Paging Mr. Herman.
- Alright? Come on.
CROW:
Come on.
TOM:
Bye.
ALL:
♪ We are the men from Texaco ♪
JOEL:
It's an army of Port-A-Potties!
CROW:
It's Eddie Murphy's entourage.
TOM:
No, it's a walk-a-thon.
CROW:
How many pledges did you get?
TOM:
Well, actually...
- Now, you Magario
may take your men
to the south gate...
Purifiante
to the north gate...
JOEL:
And Dick, you take Watergate.
- ...Pelenepo,
on his right flank,
and Hector on his left.
CROW:
Excuse me, sir,
I was really helping to be...
- And wasn't it of you
that Creon said,
"Trust that man
with your soldiers."
TOM:
Oh, everybody misquotes that.
- ...most vulnerable point.
The main gate of Thebes.
- At your command, Eteocles.
- I shall confront them...
CROW:
What, does he have his lines
written on that thing?
- ...on top of the sacred gate
of Delphi.
CROW:
Delphi rules!
TOM: Whoo!
JOEL: Kegger at Delphi!
- What is that?
JOEL:
Uh, the wind, sir?
- ...people around Thebes
taking refuge in the city, sire.
They've nowhere else to go.
- Coming out of town
without my saying so?
But there are
too many people to feed
in Thebes already.
No, back outside!
TOM: No.
- Listen, Eteocles.
The Thebans
are getting restless.
You'll be losing their favor.
TOM: Flavor?
- Yes, oh surely.
They prefer good old Creon.
JOEL:
To markers.
- But I've got a plan
for Creon.
TOM:
And it just might work.
- And now, close up the gates
to the city.
Close them!
No one is to enter
Thebes anymore!
JOEL:
And take those
ridiculous hats off.
TOM:
They're great.
JOEL:
Is this the line
for the execution?
TOM:
No, we're in line
for U2 tickets, aren't we?
CROW:
Ow, my eyes!
[♪♪♪]
JOEL:
She hasn't kissed a man
in over five minutes.
- Leave me.
TOM:
Gee, Miss Mood Swing here.
- Why did you ask me
to come here?
CROW:
I had an opening
between 3:00 and 3:30.
- You don't really want me.
TOM:
♪ Don't you want me baby ♪
- You would never understand.
- Really?
But don't you think it's simple.
You're furious
that I ask that,
and it's because you don't know
the reason for our visit. No.
TOM:
Thank you, Dr. Freud.
- And you won't
learn it from me.
- Be quiet.
- Why?
You've had enough of me?
I pity you now,
because you can never hold
Hercules.
JOEL:
You think I don't know that?
- I curse the day
he entered this palace.
JOEL:
Hey, what you talking about?
- You curse the day
I entered your palace, Omphale?
I was able to pull
the threads together.
At last I know who I am.
JOEL:
I'm big Jim McLain!
- Don't take revenge, Hercules.
TOM:
Take my wife, please.
- He wouldn't kill me.
- And what makes you
believe that?
- You yourself, Hercules.
You won't kill me
because you know
how much I love you.
CROW:
Plus, I have a restraining
order on you.
- ...sooner or later,
I'd lose you.
And so I lost you, Hercules.
TOM:
In a game of Pai gow.
- If you only knew
how I've struggled with myself
to keep from ever
falling in love with you.
But in vain.
All in vain.
- If I believed you...
JOEL:
That would be pretty funny.
- ...I would have pity on you.
- If only my sincerity
could keep you here.
- Get out.
TOM:
[indistinct].
JOEL:
It's true, it's true.
- Very well, Hercules.
CROW:
Very, very well.
- But there's one thing
you can never take away from me.
TOM:
My eyelashes.
- That the love you gave to me,
the love we shared together,
not even your Iole
can ever take that away from me.
- Don't speak to me of Iole.
We're leaving this island.
- As you wish,
Hercules of Thebes.
CROW:
I want my record collection
back.
- I will see that you and
your friends get away safely.
But go quickly
before I change my mind.
JOEL:
Just don't change your dress.
[Growling suggestively]
TOM:
♪ The minute she walked
Out the door... ♪
There she goes.
- Hercules happens
to be alive.
But Ulysses, I'm sure
that if he were alive,
he would get to us somehow.
- Sandoni, dismiss your men.
I want to be alone
with my guests.
TOM:
But--but the invitation said
orgy to follow.
JOEL:
I got seniority here, scram.
CROW:
Hey, Herc.
JOEL:
Oh, hi, Dale.
CROW:
Okay, who's got a clue
about the plot, anyone?
Bob? Rick?
Ted, you got the hat,
you must know.
JOEL:
Goodnight, everybody,
the Greek audiences
are the greatest audiences
in the world!
- Goodbye, Laertes.
Goodbye, my Greek friends.
Hercules will depart with you.
Sandoni will accompany you
to the landing.
TOM:
Zamboni?
- You know where my boy is,
tell me please!
- Hey, look out, father!
CROW:
Hey, Aunt Carol
gave us that vase.
- ...before they
leave the island.
Come on!
JOEL:
Oh.
TOM:
Oh no,
not the bass fiddle table.
JOEL:
That Pledge is really something.
CROW:
That's what that's for.
- Kill them,
kill them all, Sandoni!
But spare me Hercules.
TOM:
This is an aphrodisiac for her.
CROW:
What isn't an aphrodisiac
for her?
JOEL:
Hercules, table for eight.
CROW:
Oh, come on, he's throwing
a giant chocolate bunny.
TOM:
Wow!
Hoo-hoo.
JOEL:
Hey, we heard there
was fighting in here.
TOM:
Yes, it's Hercules.
History's first high energy
prop comic.
JOEL:
Hey, look at this!
Wah!
TOM: Whoo!
JOEL: The Hercules chess set,
send for yours today, 60609.
CROW:
There's a guy back there
throwing stuff, watch out!
TOM:
Uh, somebody want to...
Wait, I'll get it, Ulysses,
geez.
JOEL:
Uh, are we locked in or out?
CROW:
Yes.
- Ulysses, what about that story
you told me?
TOM:
Okay, let's see.
"Stately plump Buck Mulligan..."
Oh, that's not
the one you wanted, sorry.
CROW:
I went through the bushes,
into the...
Oh, this isn't
a flashback anymore.
JOEL:
Neat huh, they're great
but really pricey, guys.
Don't touch anything
you don't want to buy.
TOM:
Just think,
a couple of thousand
years from now,
their arms and noses
will all be broken off.
- Why, look, Hercules.
It was already for you.
- Come, let's hurry, there's
still time to end up here.
CROW:
It wasn't supposed to be ready
'til Thursday.
JOEL:
I don't know
where he's going,
I'm just following.
I'm a doddering old...
- Quickly,
before the door closes!
JOEL:
Wow, this is just like
Super Mario World.
[Tom humming video game music]
- This is the only way out.
Jump!
[All commentators yelling]
[Screaming and crying]
- I'm too old to jump.
- Use your mantle.
That's right.
CROW:
But white men can't jump.
- Hey, that's not part
of the-- oh.
JOEL:
Yeah, take your time.
No rush, pops.
It's around my neck!
[Choking sound]
TOM AND JOEL:
Oh!
TOM:
Oh, no. I'm okay, it's cool.
I'm fine.
- I hear the sound of the sea.
It's coming from there.
CROW:
Yeah, I guess the sea's
in that corner.
[All commentators hum
"maxwell smart" theme]
- We're all safe now.
JOEL:
Except for the oil slick.
- Better swim out to her.
CROW:
Well, when in Rome.
TOM:
They're in Greece.
- I don't know how.
- I'll carry you.
You'll be alright.
CROW:
Go to the sea, old man.
TOM:
You know, Deborah Kerr
and Burt Lancaster
must be around here somewhere.
JOEL:
Yeah, put some clothes
back on, gramps.
- ...prefer to return to Delphi.
- Come on into the water.
- I'm not afraid,
it's only that the doctors
haven't discovered
a cure for rheumatism.
CROW: [LAUGHS]
I see what you're talking about.
TOM:
Oh no.
♪ I love Hercules
And... [indistinct] ♪
JOEL:
That's good, Tom.
TOM:
♪ I'll never ever... ♪
[All gasp]
♪ I'll just die ♪
CROW:
Well, this scene oughta raise
a few eyebrows.
TOM:
♪ ...my life for Hercules ♪
JOEL:
I'm ready for my close-up,
Mr. DeMille.
TOM:
♪ I'll just die
In a pool of... ♪
I know she was spooky,
I gotta admit,
I miss her already.
[Cries]
♪ Hercules ♪
CROW:
Pull!
JOEL:
Oops, little bird poopy
on your back.
- Now, your mother
won't worry.
- My mother? No.
Mother's so courageous
she won't be upset.
I sent her for Penelope.
- The boy is growing.
- Yes, the youngsters today
think only about girls.
TOM:
Not me, sir.
- I'll never be able
to repay you.
- Just go on being our friend.
- I wouldn't worry about it.
And you'll see how long
we'll be your guests at Thebes.
- We may not even go back
to Ithaca.
[Laughing]
JOEL:
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
- ...blasted island anyway.
- About 20 days I think.
That's much longer
than we meant, too.
- Twenty days...
TOM:
Damn, I forgot
to file my quarterly.
- The time limit is up.
Polynises is
at the gates of Thebes.
TOM:
Uh-oh.
- Iole.
I've been tricked
by the gods!
TOM:
He thinks he's... [indistinct].
- She's in the hands
of that madman!
- Hoist sail and full ahead!
- Uh, Joel? Can we talk to you
for a second there?
- Sure, guys.
What's up?
How you doing?
- Oh fine.
Well, Crow and I were playing
cartoon tag
down in quadrant 12,
and we got to talking
about this movie.
We can't seem to figure out
why the Herc
is hanging around
that weird lady's place.
- Yeah, it's no big deal,
but we thought
we'd pop in here
and have you settle it for us.
- I understand,
it's no problem.
Well, this far into the film,
we know that Hercules
has drank the waters
of forgetfulness.
He doesn't know who he is,
so he's staying
with the nice lady.
- Oh, no duh.
I know that.
I guess what I'm asking is,
what does he
do there all day?
- He eats.
- Well,
well, he can't eat all day.
He's gotta be doing
something else.
- He's visiting her.
He visits.
- He's not caving in.
- Oh, come on, Joel.
You visit with your aunt,
and this woman
is nobody's aunt.
What are they doing
when they're snuggling
and kind of kissing and stuff,
and then the scene
fades out?
- Telling secrets.
Secrets.
- Okay, okay, okay.
So, Hercules,
big rugged muscley Hercules,
gets up at say 11:30,
eats some bread, fruit,
some manna,
has some spiced wine...
- Don't forget the nymphs.
- Right, right,
dropped in by one
of the 6 or 700
scantily clad nymphs.
He has some spiced wine,
takes a sauna, gets a massage,
then the nice lady
who's letting him
stay there rent-free
comes over with scented oils,
says some gushy
stuff to him,
they cuddle and smooch,
and they tell
each other some secrets...
and then what?
- He fixes her dishwasher.
I don't know,
you guys have seen
as much of the movie as I have.
Who's hungry?
- Joel, you seem nervous.
Is there something
you're not telling us?
- Yup, Joel, I think
it's time to come clean
on the whole
Hercules in Bondage thing here.
- It's Hercules Unchained, Tom.
And I think you two bots
are old enough
to know the truth about this.
Um, Hercules is the nice lady's
live-in dentist.
TOM AND CROW:
Oh, I get it.
Hey!
- What a rip-off!
- That's no fair.
- Come on, you guys.
Eat your raisins.
You go on ahead,
I have to iron this out.
They're nature's candy.
- No, I don't want 'em.
- Okay, catch it.
Come on, you ready?
[♪♪♪]
- Hercules,
by the gods...
TOM:
Live-in dentist? Ack.
CROW:
I think I know what it was.
- Your woman is going to
provide a spectacle for us.
And the day I get you,
she'll be held for the tigers.
JOEL:
The Detroit Tigers?
CROW:
No.
- And the others?
Stand back now.
Here's my answer, Polynises.
Look at your supporters...
TOM:
They're not wearing supporters.
- You'll be next.
Yes, you're next!
CROW:
You're next to the statue.
[Screaming]
[All commentators booing]
TOM:
They hit Newton.
JOEL:
Say what you want,
the guy's got
a great sense of humor.
CROW:
Weird.
Really weird.
TOM:
That wasn't really that funny.
Must be some obscure
Greek observational humor
or something, I don't know.
CROW:
Well, to each his own.
TOM:
Yup.
ALL COMMENTATORS:
♪ Sing around the campfire ♪
♪ Join the campfire Greeks ♪
- Eteocles mustn't see you.
- He waits only for that
in order to kill your wife.
She'll die before your eyes...
[indistinct]
It'll be the climax
to everything.
TOM:
Okay, okay.
- Throw her to the tigers.
CROW:
Or the Euphrates,
it doesn't make much difference.
JOEL:
Does that bug you?
- We're prepared to help you,
Hercules.
We'll do whatever you want.
But you must be careful.
TOM:
You'll have to speak
at your sister's school
on career day.
CROW:
There goes
one of the dumbest guys
you'll ever meet.
Ouch!
- ...all of our forces
against one gate
because the Thebans are there.
It's only because
you want to...
TOM: What is going on?
- ...with Eteocles.
- It would be better
to have the attack
come as a surprise.
- My brother is mad,
but he is ingenious.
He can be sure
about our going into battle
when the Thebans
have the sun in their eyes.
TOM:
Oh, for the clarity of
Mighty Jack at this point.
- ...in the city anymore?
- Well, our impression is
that they're eliminated.
- There are still a great many
that are loyal to me.
- Our information
is to the contrary.
The people want Creon,
they say.
- That isn't true.
I guarantee you about it.
- And who guarantees us
about you?
CROW:
Lloyds of London.
- An emissary from Thebes.
Bearing a message.
TOM:
Mystery guest,
enter and sign in, please!
CROW:
Nah, you guys are supposed to
stop bogging down the movie.
- ...to speak to you, Polynises.
He offers to settle the rule
of Thebes with a duel.
Just you and he alone.
That is why
I bring this to you now.
JOEL:
It's your GED.
- A duel? Not a bad idea.
TOM:
We could get Dennis Weaver.
- How about it, Polynises.
- I must think about it.
- It means peace now,
Polynises.
- Of course,
it's much better to duel.
- Not afraid by any chance,
Polynises?
CROW: [IMITATING]
Not afraid by any chance,
Polynises?
- But who'll assure us
the bargain's respected.
- All of us Thebans.
I'm only telling you that
we're weary of these quarrels.
Of the bloodshed.
JOEL:
We, we, w-really?
TOM:
W-really w-really.
JOEL: Wow.
- But you may lose, Polynises.
You may die.
Will they get out of the city
and return to their houses?
Do you promise that?
CROW:
I'm chilly,
will you get me a wrap?
- I assure you.
TOM:
I'm bald.
Owie, crayfish, ouch.
Now, that divides
the kiddie pool
from the adult pool there.
[Humming with soundtrack]
CROW:
He's getting the bends.
[Laughs]
TOM:
Good one.
JOEL:
Tonight on Garrison Guerillas,
a rag tag band of rebels
are taking on the Greeks.
CROW:
Hey, this water's warm here.
Herc!
TOM:
Aw, geez.
- Aesculapius.
TOM:
You Aesculapius, I'm bitter.
- Oh gods, please protect me!
CROW:
It's the newest sport,
grandpa dunking.
JOEL:
He's gonna rust
like everything now.
CROW: Where's grandpa?
TOM: The first Stairmaster.
- Wasn't that Hercules?
JOEL:
Hey, we're just trying
to sell you baskets!
TOM:
Ho, ho.
Whoa, guys.
CROW:
Very into it.
The Ramada Inn
wants their towels back.
JOEL:
Hey, anybody seen
my Social Security check?
I must've dropped it.
'Cause he's old, you see.
TOM:
What?
Oh, criminy, I wandered
onto the Spartacus set, ack.
JOEL:
Uh, sir? We're closed.
CROW:
Guys?
Hey, this isn't funny anymore.
[Shouting and laughing]
[All commentators
imitate laughing]
TOM:
Hercules and the thing's
smelly butt.
[Laughs]
ALL COMMENTATORS:
♪ She's a man eater ♪
JOEL:
I gotta admit, it's funny.
[Growling]
TOM:
Okay.
Nice camera work,
good tiger's butt there.
CROW:
Hey, didn't he pull a thorn
out of that tiger's paw?
TOM:
That was Androcles.
[Shouting]
CROW:
Hobbes, get off of me.
TOM:
Come on,
pretend you're biting me,
I work for tips.
CROW:
Nice kitty.
TOM:
Akiba!
[All commentators booing]
CROW:
You killed my dad,
you freaked out maniac!
TOM:
I'm Charlton Heston's
[indistinct].
CROW:
I'm hungry for a Manwich!
Heh-heh.
JOEL:
Cat scratch fever!
TOM:
I'll say.
You drop that ball,
drop that ball, drop it!
Drop it.
Drop it, you drop it.
CROW:
Oh hi, we just thought
we'd stop by
and see what's...
Jimkata!
TOM:
Oh look, it's
a Smurfs vs. the skins here.
CROW:
Take your time, Ulysses.
[All commentators booing]
TOM:
I hate that.
JOEL:
He hit big Jake.
Spare the rod,
spoil the child,
spare the rod,
and spoil the child.
TOM:
Ah, it says "pull."
CROW:
Look, Herc's got a red butt.
[Tom chuckling]
CROW:
Knock knock, ha!
[♪♪♪]
TOM:
Do you know, if somebody'd
invent boxing,
they'd save
a lot of time here.
CROW: Do you want to go?
JOEL: Yeah, sure.
Your place?
TOM:
I'll be right back,
I forgot something.
I'll catch you
on the flip flop, okay?
JOEL:
Now it's just me and you,
mono a mono.
CROW:
Tonight, it's Abe Vigoda
vs. James Whitmore
in a battle to the death.
TOM:
You know, there's no bad seats
in this theater.
JOEL:
You know, I was just wondering
where Hercules went?
CROW:
I wonder where the movie went?
TOM:
Mmm-hmm.
CROW:
Ya cut me, ya jerk!
TOM:
Hello.
My name is Inigo Montoya,
you killed my father,
prepare to die.
JOEL:
They're fighting over
who had that hairstyle first.
CROW:
I look like Lucy!
JOEL:
No, I look like Lucy!
[Screaming]
TOM:
Now he's the "knight,"
of the Living Dead.
[Laughing]
- This guy finds
the funny side of everything.
TOM:
Thank you,
now for my next trick,
I need a volunteer
from the audience.
- Thebans,
pray to the gods,
because at last
Eteocles has won the day
and is victorious!
[Cheering]
TOM:
Uh-huh, yeah.
And Dewey defeats Truman,
right?
CROW:
He's no fun, he fell right over.
JOEL:
What a letdown.
CROW:
And now, a prayer.
TOM:
And now I suppose
I gotta go clean up.
For crying out loud.
[Horse whinnies]
JOEL:
I know,
I feel the same way horse.
CROW:
Come on, get up.
Still gotta go to school, dummy.
TOM:
The redhead is dead.
- ...stupid as his brother.
They deserve to end this way.
CROW:
He learned to late
that man is a feeling creature
and because of it,
the greatest in the universe.
He learned to late for himself
that men have to make
their own way...
JOEL:
Yeah, yeah.
- Hercules!
You see this?
Well, I shall celebrate
this victory.
She's in my house now.
And I'm going there.
CROW:
And I've got cable.
TOM:
Uh, what time
should I come over?
You want me
to bring something?
- Get to your posts!
JOEL:
Get my purse!
TOM:
You know, this is like
I, Claudius,
only it's not good at all.
JOEL:
You know,
they really are talented.
They put on such a great show,
you know.
They give 110 percent
over there, you know...
used to work with them.
Wonderful.
TOM:
Oh yeah, oh yeah.
CROW:
Let's break off
and start another movie.
Ha, look. Looks like
they got the leftover parts
from an airplane model.
TOM:
It's the world's largest
chess set.
JOEL:
It's a traveling rest stop.
- Well, look at that.
The Thebans are abandoning
their defenses.
TOM:
Oh. You see that?
- They must be surrendering
the town.
CROW:
Looks like they brought
the whole darn town with them!
JOEL:
It's Ted Koppel's head,
look out!
[All commentators shouting]
CROW:
Hey, come on, interrupt
you gladiators!
TOM:
Ladies and gentlemen,
Elvis Presley!
[All commentators
humming elvis intro]
And know that each float
is made of 75,000 individual
fresh flowers put in place.
JOEL:
Wayland Flowers?
TOM:
Yup, yup.
JOEL:
Yup, I'm the title character.
That's me pretty much.
Herc, your friend.
Hi.
TOM:
Hey, does anybody have any idea
what we're doing here?
CROW:
I thought you knew.
TOM:
No!
Change into makeup
for the Chariot of Montauk.
Oh, thank you.
JOEL:
This kind of reminds me
of the Empire Strikes Back
except it's not very good.
TOM:
Yeah, I know what you mean.
[All commentators shouting]
[Tom humming]
CROW:
Hercules, those are our guys,
you idiot!
TOM:
Oh, now here comes
the Boston Marathon.
- Where is the cavalry?
CROW:
That's not my 'partment,
Captain Brittles.
TOM:
Yeah, yeah.
I know, once more
into the breach, I know.
[All commentators booing]
TOM: I hate that.
CROW: I'm calling Betty White.
TOM:
And I'm calling Tippi Hedren.
JOEL:
And I'm calling Bridget Bardot.
[Crow yelling quickly
and indistinctly]
JOEL:
It's like the end
of a Mel Brooks movie.
[Shouting]
Mmm-hmm, that's good tower.
CROW:
Checkmate.
TOM:
Oh, look.
It's the Sisters of St. Francis.
JOEL:
Last day of school's
always like this.
CROW:
Nutty.
TOM:
And die.
Thank you.
Okay everybody, off the set.
We're trying to clear the set
for the end of the movie.
Please leave the set now.
Thank you.
JOEL:
Oh boy.
TOM:
Bye now.
CROW:
Epilogue.
JOEL:
Spalding Gray?
- The thieves took revenge
on Oedipus and his sons too.
JOEL:
And his friend Chopper
who's real fun.
- ...for inciting the gods.
Now with these flames
they purify our city
and those who shall stay.
TOM:
Or something like that,
I think,
uh, you'll have to excuse me,
I'm really hung over.
CROW:
Oh, honey?
About all that
oinking and boinking
I did on the island?
Well, it was nothing.
- How much you suffered, Iole.
The gods have placed
many obstacles against us
and there'll be others.
TOM:
Yeah, well, you're sleeping
on the couch, Herc.
- I hope we shall
withstand them.
Somehow the gods will be kind
if we just love one another.
JOEL:
Are they in heaven?
Now Herc, no more
business trips, okay?
TOM:
This is the end of
the story of forgetfulness.
Those who watch it
will die of boredom.
[Growls]
JOEL:
Stinky.
- Hey, Joelster,
why these kind of movies?
- Well,
that's a good question, Gypsy.
However,
there aren't any simple answers.
- Well, yes there are.
- I think maybe
it's a cultural thing.
You know, the post-war era.
- Right,
that's exactly right, Crow.
You know, Western culture
had a real need
during the Cold War
for fantastic spectacle.
- Yeah, spectacles.
- Yeah, it's true.
After Liz Taylor accepted
over a million dollars
for a role in Cleopatra,
you know,
big budget blockbusters
became the coin of the realm.
- No, wrong guys, wrong.
- I was thinking
more along the lines
of European indignation
toward post-war conservatism
and sexual repression
which translated
onto the screen
into big sweaty guys
pushing girls around.
- Crow, you are so high.
- No, come on,
Crow's got a point.
Without sex,
would Hercules Unchained
even been made?
- Joseph Campbell.
ALL:
Huh?
- Joseph Campbell?
- Oh.
What-- I think
what our bright young friend
is trying to remind us of
is the need for myth.
You know?
The collective dream.
- Yeah, yeah.
There's a need
for gods and heroes.
I remember
that Joseph Campbell
said something
in one of those books of his
with masks and stuff in it
and that this thing,
you're supposed to do--
- Wrong, wrong,
wrong, wrong...
- Come on, I think
we can probe deeper
into the phenomela--
phenume--
- Phenomenological.
- Yeah, I think we can
probe deeper into
the phenomenological basis
for Hercules' experience.
- Discarding
the classical dualistic view
of course, and--
- How do you figure?
- Oh, well, Gypsy,
every phenomenon
belongs to our regional ontology
by virtue of its essence.
- Look, I'll make it easy
for all of you!
Joseph E. Levine
picked these turkeys up
after a sagging European box
drove the price way down,
then he dumped them,
brought them to America,
did a massive distribution deal
and made a fortune, okay?
- You're wrong.
- Oh.
- Philistine.
- Tom.
- Well, well, it's true.
Am I right, sirs?
I mean, come on,
back me up on this.
- Yeah.
Oh, well.
Steve, is that right?
- Uh, yeah I guess so.
I mean, there were
these guys in suits
that used to drive up the coast
and check on us
every now and then.
I didn't really
get to meet them much.
I was usually up on the cliffs
drinking that wine
they got there.
It's really cheap,
it's about 13 cents a bottle.
- Thank you, Steve.
- Yeah, no problem.
- Well, 'til next time...
[indistinct]
Push the button, Frank.
- Hey, I dig your hair, man.
- Frank!
- Can I have your autograph?
- Oh, okay.
- Are you any relation
to Keanu Reeves?
[♪♪♪]